Privacy Policy

Overview

The protection of personal information is important to the Vancouver Regional Construction

Association (VRCA). The VRCA is committed to maintaining the accuracy, security and privacy

of personal information in accordance with applicable legislation. This VRCA privacy policy is a

statement of principles and guidelines concerning the protection of personal information of our

customers, service providers and other individuals (“you”). Any questions about this policy can

be directed to our privacy officer, VRCA Director of Operations, Roxanne Schutz (phone 604-

293-6583 / roxanne@vrca.ca).

Our employees play an important role in protecting personal information. Our employees are

required to adhere to this policy and take all reasonable steps to ensure that personal

information is protected from unauthorized access.

Consent

By submitting personal information to the VRCA, you agree that we may collect, use and

disclose such personal information in accordance with this privacy policy and as permitted or

required by law. Subject to legal and contractual requirements, you may refuse or withdraw your

consent to certain of the identified purposes at any time by contacting the VRCA Privacy Officer.

If you refuse or withdraw your consent, the VRCA may be unable to provide you or continue to

provide you with certain services, programs and/or information which may be of value to you.

If you provide the VRCA with personal information of another individual, you represent that you

have all necessary authority and/or have obtained all necessary consents from such person to

enable the VRCA to collect, use and disclose such personal information for the purposes set

forth in this privacy policy.

Collection of personal information

Canadian privacy legislation defines “personal information” broadly as information about an

identifiable individual or as information that allows an individual to be identified. For the

purposes of this policy, “personal information” means information about an identifiable individual

as defined from time to time in applicable privacy legislation. Personal information does not

include what is considered business contact information generally found on a business card (i.e.

name, title, business number, business fax number, business email address, etc.).

Although the VRCA deals commonly with member companies at the organizational and

employee level, we also deal with individual customers. We collect the personal information of

our individual customers in administering the following:

Registration for VRCA’s education courses/workshops/conferences/events/meetings;

Sponsorship of VRCA’s education courses/workshops/conferences/events/meetings;

Printing and scanning services offered by VRCA’s planroom;

Advertising orders for VRCA’s media opportunities;

Purchase of construction documents (CCA, CCDC) and Canadian Design Build Manuals;

Commissioner of Oath Services (Statutory Declarations) in British Columbia for construction

documents only.

For the purposes of providing Commissioner of Oath Services, the VRCA does not collect

personal information however does verify the identity of individuals via photo identification in

person.

When individual customers or ‘registrants’ submitting requests for another individual register for

VRCA’s education courses, workshops, conferences, events or meetings we may collect the

following types of personal information:

name;

spouse’s name;

children’s name(s);

home address, telephone number, and fax number;

email address;

dietary requirements; and

credit card information.

For the purposes of providing support to users for sponsorship opportunities, printing and

scanning services, advertising opportunities, the purchase of construction documents (CCA,

CCDC) and Canadian Design Build Manuals, the VRCA may collect the following types of

personal information:

name;

email address;

registration number;

credit card information

Use of personal information

The personal information collected by the VRCA is used for the following purposes:

to contact the individual for instruction;

to issue invoices, administer accounts, collect and process payments;

to send VRCA course/workshop/conference/event/meeting enrollment confirmation;

to plan and arrange for needs while in attendance at a VRCA

course/workshop/conference/event/meeting;

to develop, enhance, market, sell or otherwise provide VRCA’s products and services;

to include you on our mailing list for VRCA bulletins and event notices;

to comply with any legal or regulatory requirements or provisions;

for any other purpose to which you consent.

We only collect personal information directly from the individual except when the ‘registrant’ is

submitting the request on behalf of another individual or are permitted by law to collect it without

the individual’s consent.

We use an individual’s personal information strictly for the purposes outlined above. If we need

to use the personal information for any other purpose we will contact the individual and obtain

consent prior to that use.

Disclosure of personal information

From time to time, the VRCA may disclose your personal information to:

• service providers, including an organization or individual retained by VRCA to provide

savings and/or affinity programs and services;

• any third party or parties, where you consent to such disclosure or where disclosure is

required or permitted by law.

When we disclose your personal information to third parties, we require such parties to maintain

levels of confidentiality and security, in addition to obtaining such third parties’ representation of

the implementation of their own privacy policy.

An individual has the right to withdraw consent for our collection, use or disclosure of their

personal information at any time. However, if an individual does so it may affect his/her ability to

participate in programs and/or receive services provided by the VRCA. If an individual wishes to

withdraw consent, or has any questions about withdrawing consent, he or she can contact our

privacy officer.

Business contact information is not protected by this policy. This type of information is not

considered to be personal information and may be collected, used and disclosed without

consent.

Storage of personal information

The VRCA has appropriate safeguards in place to protect personal information. The VRCA

takes all reasonable precautions to ensure that your personal information is kept safe from loss,

unauthorized access, modification or disclosure. Among the steps taken to protect your

personal information are:

premises security;

restricted file access to personal information;

technological safeguards such as security software and firewalls to prevent hacking or

unauthorized computer access;

internal password and security policies;

proper training of VRCA’s employees in respect of privacy matters.

Accuracy of personal information

We try to keep personal information as accurate as possible and individuals can assist us by

providing us with updated information when necessary. Information can be updated by

contacting VRCA privacy officer and director of operations, Roxanne Schutz.

Retention of personal information

We only keep personal information for as long as is necessary for the purposes outlined above.

This may include keeping the information after a service or program has been completed in

order to resolve any problems or concerns that may arise. We are also required by law to

maintain certain records for set amounts of time.

Access

Individuals have the right to access the personal information we hold about them. You can

access your personal information by making a request to our Privacy Officer. The Officer will

provide the necessary forms and assistance to make the request and obtain the information. If

you believe that some of the personal information is incorrect you can request that the

information be corrected.

Accountability

We apply our best efforts to protect your privacy. If an individual has any concerns they are free

to contact our privacy officer. We hope that the Officer will be able to resolve any problems. If

concerns are not resolved, the Officer can provide information on making a formal complaint.

Employment inquiries

If you apply for employment at the VRCA, we will require your personal information as part of

our review process. We normally retain information from candidates after a decision has been

made, unless you ask us not to retain the information. If we offer you a job, which you accept,

the information will be retained in accordance with our privacy procedures for employee records.

Website

VRCA’s website may contain links to other sites, which are not governed by this privacy policy.

On our website, like most other commercial websites, we may monitor traffic patterns, site

usage and related site information in order to optimize our web service. We may provide

aggregated information to third parties, but these statistics do not include any identifiable

personal information.

Photo \& Video Disclaimer

The Vancouver Regional Construction Association reserves the right to use any

photograph/video taken at any event sponsored by VRCA, without the expressed written

permission of those included within the photograph/video. VRCA may use the photograph/video

in publications or other media material produced including but not limited to: brochures,

newsletters, newspapers, magazines, websites, etc.

To ensure the privacy of individuals and children, images will not be identified using full names

or personal identifying information without written approval from the photographed subject,

parent or legal guardian.

A person attending a VRCA event who does not wish to have their image recorded for

distribution should make their wishes known to the photographer, and/or the event organizers,

and/or contact VRCA 3636 E 4th Avenue, Vancouver BC V5M 1M3 in writing of his/her

intentions and include a photograph. The VRCA will use the photo for identification purposes

and will hold it in confidence.

By participating in a VRCA event or by failing to notify VRCA, in writing, your desire to not have

your photograph used, you are agreeing to release, defend, hold harmless and indemnify VRCA

from any and all claims involving the use of your picture or likeness.

Any person or organization not affiliated with VRCA may not use, copy, alter or modify VRCA

photographs, graphics, videography or other, similar reproductions or recordings without the

advance written permission of an authorized designee from VRCA.

Amendment of this privacy policy

The VRCA will from time to time review and revise its privacy practices and this privacy policy.

In the event of any amendment, an appropriate notice will be posted on VRCA’s website.

Contact information

Vancouver Regional Construction Association

Privacy officer

3636 E 4th Avenue

Vancouver, BC V5M 1M3

roxanne@vrca.ca

Tel: 604-293-6583
